MANIMARAN SELVAN

TECHNOPRENEUR | STRATEGIC THINKER | VISIONARY

mselvan@belyf.com | +91-994-018-1901 | https://blog.belyf.com/ | https://linkedin.com/in/maniselvan/



SUMMARY

With 15+ years in software engineering and 6 years in technical product management, I've led initiatives that have significantly boosted efficiency and growth. Known for high-impact strategic decision-making, and collaborative leadership, I excel in nurturing high-performing teams and processes.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Strategic Planning, Leadership & Team Collaboration, Agile & Lean Methodologies, Continuous Improvement, Product Vision & Mission, Vendor Management, Stakeholder Management, Change Management, Software Engineering, Decision Making, Coaching/Mentoring, People Management, Cross-functional Collaboration, Conflict Resolution, Emerging Technologies

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Java, Groovy, Javascript, Python, AWS, GCP, API Gateway, AppSync, Lambda, EventBridge, Step Functions, Gradle, Maven, Jenkins, UAT Testing, Alpha/Beta Testing, A/B Testing, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Neptune, Redis, Athena, Docker, K8s, REST, GraphQL, Git, SVN, CVS, Figma, Balsamiq, SNS, Kinesis, Kafka, Lucidchart, Draw.io, Quicksight, Grafana

CERTIFICATES

<u>Aha! Product Management Professional</u> <u>Certificate</u>

<u>freeCodeCamp – Javascript Algorithms and Data</u> <u>Structures</u>

EDUCATION

B.Sc Computer Science, Bharathidasan University, Trichy, India. 2008

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Co-founded 2 startups; led IT consolidation, saving \$4.3M/year.
- Contributed to CloudFix specs, yielding \$15M+ internal and \$100M+ customer savings.
- Increased throughput 5x via SLA-driven assembly lines; authored 100+ technical specs.
- Led post-acquisition of Jive (\$462M), reducing the TCO by 90%.
- Scored top 1% in CCAT; modernized legacy software, reducing millions of LOC to 5K.
- Led architecture for 10+ software platforms, delivered on time and within budget.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Enterprises, Inc.

Austin, Texas (Remote)

Technical Product Manager, Central TPM founding member.

Aug 2018 – Jun 2023

- Led initiatives saving \$15M+, Productized strategies resulting in \$100M+ savings.
- Implemented assembly lines, enabling 24/7 operations for a 5K+ global workforce.
- Co-managed 60+ TPMs with retiring VP, preparing for VP role.
- Developed tools for spec ordering, search, stack ranking, and CTO bootcamps.

Lead Software Engineer, Acting IT Ops Manager.

Jan 2015 - Jul 2018

- Centralized IT Ops for 5K+ global workforce, achieving 85% cost savings.
- Coached and managed 20+ senior SREs making them deliver 4x value.
- Authored M&A IT transition playbooks resulting in integrating 15+ acquisitions.
- Set up JIRA workflows and automation resulting in enterprise-wide unified process.

Tissow Technology Ventures, LLP.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Nov 2013 – Dec 2014

- Delivered Humingo, an e-commerce aggregation platform in a span of 6 months.
- Modernized Ticketgoose, a bus ticket booking and operator management platform, in 3 months with new tech and simplified architecture.
- Optimized tech operations reducing TCO by 50%.

Nallan Technology Ventures Private Limited.

Chennai, India

Technical Lead.

Dec 2011 - Oct 2013

• Steered the architecture and deployment of Kachyng, a PCI-compliant mobile payments platform with single-click checkout and ads.

EMRG Software Solutions Private Limited.

Chennai, India
Sep 2010 – Nov 2011

Technical Co-founder.

(Originally from Aug 2009)

• Hired and managed a 10-member team in software engineering and SaaS, developing two software products in financial information research space.

YuMe, Inc.

Chennai, India

Systems Engineer

Jan 2010 - Aug 2010

 Managed infrastructure and automated deployments across 6 internal environments; oversaw bi-weekly production deployments, weekly migrations, and daily DevOps tasks.

Java Application Developer.

Aug 2008 - Dec 2009

 Pioneered R&D in early mobile technologies and delivered native apps; created proofof-concepts in Google Web Toolkit.

For a more detailed resume, please visit https://mselvan.com/?mode=comprehensive.